JOSEPH UMBA

Cape Town | + 27 849664077 | <u>Josephdjamba04@gmail.com</u> Portfolio: <u>stately-madeleine-04e1a4.netlify.app/</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Software Developer with 3+ years of experience, eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail, and excellent organizational skills, with a strong passion for software development. Motivated to continuously learn, grow, and excel in the IT industry. Seeking a mid-level role, which will provide commercial exposure and opportunities for progression.

PRIMARY SKILLS

TECHNOLOGIES

C# (.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, Web API) | SQL Server | JavaScript, React.js | Azure (App Services, DevOps CI/CD) | Relational Database Design | Gitlab | API testing Postman | Agile Methodology | Domain Driven Design | Spring Framework | Test Automation

IDE

Visual Studio 2022, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, MySQL Workbench

SECONDARY SKILLS

Process Modeling Documentation | Project | Planning | Project Management | UI/UX Design | Mock-Ups | Excellent Problem-Solving | Adaptability | Time Management

EDUCATION

BTech- November 2024

Bachelor's degree in Information and Technology Application Development, Cape Peninsula University of Technology.

NDip- November 2022

National Diploma in Information and Technology Application Development, Cape Peninsula University of Technology.

ADDITIONAL COURSES

- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Microsoft (Ongoing)
- The complete Full-Stack Web development Bootcamp Udemy Academy
- Build ASP .NET Core Web API Scratch to Finish Udemy Academy
- Software Architecture LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pilot Software Holdings (CPT)

Software Developer / May 2024 - Present (18 Months)

Point of Sale systems

- 1. Develop and Maintain responsive React, Angular user interface
- 2. Build and maintain C#.NET Core / ASP.NET MVC backend services and APIs
- 3. Model and maintain SQL Server databases (SSMS)
- 4. Deploy applications to web hosting environments (Azure)
- 5. Collaborate effectively with remote and on-site teams in an Agile environment

Dynamic Web Services (CPT)

Junior Software Engineer / November 2022 – March 2024 (16 Months)

Plum systems

- 1. Define Requirements Specification Doc
- 2. Web Applications UI design
- 3. Implement UI design React
- 4. Connect application to SQL Database
- 5. Deploy to Web hosting Service

Automated E-commerce Website Testing

- 1. Develop automated test scripts using Selenium WebDriver
- 2. Create test cases for different user scenarios
- 3. Integrate tests into the continuous integration pipeline (Jenkins)

SIM OFFICE(CPUT)

Junior Java Developer / May 2022 – Oct 2022 (6 Months)

- 1. Define Requirements Specification Document
- 2. Perform Data modeling for applications
- 3. Application Front-end Design
- 4. Maintain and refactor the code where necessary

5. API Testing Using POSTMAN

Mobile App Testing Automation

- 1. Collaborate with the mobile development team to automate testing of a mobile appusing Java
- 2. Implement test cases for various app functionalities such as user authentication, navigation, and form submissions
- 3. Execute tests on multiple mobile devices and reported defects using JIRA

Projects

Game – Store (Web App Development, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB) / April 2024 – Present

• Developing E-commerce Website to sale Video games and accessories.

Languages

English

Hobbies

- Coding for personal project
- Reading

References

Available upon request